# **BENJAMIN BILLINGSLEY**

Casa Grande, Arizona, USA ● 314 435 4499 ● bbill010@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/benjaminbillingsley/ | github.com/benjaminbillingsley

### **SUMMARY STATEMENT**

I'm a future cybersecurity professional who is consistently learning and building experience to enter this new career path. My passion and purpose stem from my military service where I seek to help others, defend those who can't do it themselves, and protect individuals and businesses from the constant threat of cyber-attacks

### **EDUCATION**

## B.S., Accounting, Grand Canyon University, 2024

A.S., Emergency Response & Operations, Paradise Valley Community College, 2019

A.A., Business, Montgomery College – Rockville, 2016

#### TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Languages: Python, HTML, SQL, BASH, Windows CLI.

Platforms: Windows, MacOS, Linux (Ubuntu, Debian), iOS, Android.

Concepts: NMAP, Wireshark, Splunk, Metasploit, Windows Defender, Virtual Box, OpenVPN, Burp Suite, OSINT, Spiderfoot, Shodan.io, Microsoft Office Suite, NIST Frameworks, ITIL v4, ISO 27001, MFA, Zero Trust.

Expertise In: Troubleshooting, adding/removing programs, firewall management, user management, virtualization, performance management, backup and restoring, customer service, ticket management, active directory, policy management, auditing, analysis, critical thinking.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certified in Cybersecurity – ISC2 #1700876

Google Cybersecurity - Coursera

Google IT Support Professional - Coursera

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Business Operations Associate, TEKsystems, 2021-Present

- Manage accounts receivable book between 8-10 million dollars for a major client. My organization and prioritization skills ensure my books has zero to minimal issues, accurate and timely invoicing, and ontime payment collections.
- Review and interpret contractual agreements such as purchase orders, statements of work, and service agreements.
- Advanced Microsoft Excel skills to create ad-hoc reports, display financial data, and combining data from multiple documents.
- Problem solving and critical thinking skills are highlighted due to the need for investigating outstanding issues, explaining impacts of issues to leadership, and teamwork with coworkers as well.

• Serve as the IT/Cybersecurity champion in my office to help address questions and issues from a non-administrator standpoint.

# Senior Project Operations Associate, TEKsystems, 2022-2023

- Pioneered this role at the Tempe corporate office which helped establish the transition of this role and eventually other roles in the Global Services department from the main HQ on the East Coast. We started with 5 employees and have grown to over 50 in a 2-year timeframe.
- Persevered through the change from my previous role as a BOA while training to be a POA. I had to
  perform both roles for about a month, ensuring my accounts receivable book was well maintained until
  I could transition to a new employee.

## Field Supervisor, U.S. Census Bureau, 2020

- Led a team of 14 enumerators of diverse backgrounds and ages for a temporary government assignment that required transparent communication, coaching, management of documents, auditing and approving time sheets, training, and support.
- Maintained the security for confidential government documents and personal private information (PII) in storage and in-transit to the field office.

# Enterprise Business Development Representative, Nextiva, 2016-2018

- Served to expand the company's customer base by using marketing strategies to identify prospects and initiate outreach with potential customers to book meetings and fill the pipelines for the sales team.
- Adapted to a regularly changing environment in terms of organizational changes, quota changes, and process changes.
- Leveraged strong communication skills to cultivate strong relationships with customers from initial contact to the closing of the deal; provided effective after—sales service to promote future business.

# Manager, California Pizza Kitchen, 2014-2016

- As a manager I would service the restaurant as whole, placing myself in areas of need such as the kitchen, take-out counter, serving tables, expediting food, host stand, and bussing as needed. This helped ensure a happy and low stress workforce and smooth-running operation.
- Built this location's catering and delivery program though door-to-door marketing and word of mouth.
   Researched local businesses and who to talk to. This quickly became a hit and by the time I left, the take-out/delivery section was about 1/3 of total sales.

# Petty Officer 3rd Class, U.S. Navy, 2009-2016

- Served in both the active (2009 2014) and reserve (2014 2016) components of the US Navy.
- As a Hospital Corpsman I consistently learn trends and updated to healthcare protocols. Troubleshoot and diagnose health related issues in both hospital and field settings.
- Volunteered to serve on the base Auxiliary Security Force where I learned law enforcement and physical security skills and concepts. Regularly stood duty at points-of-entry where I was the first line of defense to any threats against our base.
- Deployment to Afghanistan 2012-2013 where I received an Army Commendation Medal for exemplary service that ensured a smooth running and well-stocked trauma center.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

Billingsley, B. (April, 2024). "Third-Party Risk Management (TPRM): Navigating the Present and Anticipating the Future". *LinkedIn*. [Article].

Billingsley, B. (September, 2022). "Career Success: Goals". LinkedIn. [Article].

### **CONTINUING EDUCATION**

TryHackMe.com – 55 courses(rooms) completed, rank top 8%.

HackTheBox.com – Currently working through some fundamental level courses.

CodeAcademy.com – Currently improving SQL and Python skills.

EC-Council – Currently enrolled in the Certified Cybersecurity Technician (CCT) course and other various cybersecurity specific courses to learn new skills and knowledge.

Cybrary.it – When time permits I go in here to continue learning and brushing up on IT, risk, and cybersecurity concepts and knowledge.

SkillsForAll (Cisco Academy) – Currently refreshing and developing my knowledge in networking.

#### **PROJECTS**

- Used HTML and CSS to create my own resume/portfolio website. I did use a template that I learned but
  was able to manipulate it and understand the concepts of what I needed to do. Used GitHub to publish
  it online.
- Created a batch script using Windows CLI and PowerShell at my current job. The PowerShell portion
  opens and downloads a file from our company Sharepoint (CMD Prompt didn't work for this I learned).
  The Windows CLI portions open a file template, open the explorer to the folder where I need to save
  files, then creates a new folder with the current date for whatever day the script is ran. This saves me
  about 5-10 minutes rather than doing all these steps individually.
- I created a Windows CLI template that changes directory to where I need it to, then creates multiple directories and sub-directories for a particular type of folder. This saves a lot of time by not having to create a new folder and rename them individually.

#### PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

ISC2 - Member ID 1700876

## SKILLS, INTERESTS, AND HOBBIES

Skills: Fast learner, understands and grasps complex theories and processes, responsible, curious, resilient, handles stress well, team player, leadership, management, creative, coachable, growth mindset.

Interests: Self-improvement, ethical hacking/penetration testing, risk management, SOC analyst, governance risk and compliance (GRC), blue team, red team. Aspire to be a CISO or Director level.

Hobbies: Learn and write my own songs on guitar and piano (self-taught on both), cooking food from various cuisines/ethnicities, video games, traveling, collecting books for my home library, intentional time with my family.